{
  "q1": [
    {
      "question": "As aide-de-camp to Robert E. Lee, this man delivered the surrender ultimatum to John Brown before the latter was captured at Harpers Ferry. During the Peninsular Campaign, this man, who was known for his “cavalier” image, conducted the “Ride around McClellan.” This man was mortally wounded at the Battle of Yellow Tavern and was known as the “eyes and ears” of his army. For ten points, name this Confederate general who commanded the cavalry of the Army of Northern Virginia.",
      "answer": "James Ewell Brown “Jeb” Stuart A"
    },
    {
      "question": "This man led an expedition in which men in testudo formation could not advance to meet the enemy Parthian horse archers. This man was executed by having molten gold poured down his throat to represent his wealth. Before his defeat at Carrhae, this leader crucified several thousand people after successfully defeating the revolt of Spartacus. For ten points, name this enormously rich Roman general who was a member of the First Triumvirate alongside Pompey and Caesar.",
      "answer": "Marcus Licinius Crassus"
    },
    {
      "question": "In this film, Kenneth Dahlberg is questioned about a $25,000 check he sent to certain individuals. R In this film, the address books of two criminals are found to include references to CIA officer, E. Howard Hunt. Jason Robards won an Oscar for his portrayal of editor Ben Bradlee in this film. This film stars Robert Redford and Dustin Hoffman. Based on a book written by its central characters, Bob Woodward and Carl Bernstein, for ten points, name this 1976 film about the Watergate scandal.",
      "answer": "All the President’s Men"
    },
    {
      "question": "This country’s leader banned the Birilik opposition party and may have kidnapped his own nephew, Jamshid. Hundreds of protestors in this country were massacred in Bobur Square in 2005 in Andijan. That D massacre in this country was supposed retribution against the Islamist Hizb-ut Tahrir. British ambassador Craig Murray claims that two dissidents in this country were boiled alive by its president, Islam Karimov. For ten points, name this member of the Commonwealth of Independent States.",
      "answer": "Republic of Uzbekistan"
    },
    {
      "question": "Deadly riots during the grand opening of this location inspired a similar structure, designed by Renzo Piano, to be placed on an artificial island. Goryo Farm was absorbed during the construction of this location which was the subject of the decade-long Sanrizuka Struggle. Construction on this location began after projections predicting that Haneda Airport would reach capacity by 1970. Japan Airlines has its main hub at, for ten points, what international airport serving Tokyo?",
      "answer": [
        "Narita International Airport",
        "Narita Kokusai Kuko",
        "Tokyo Narita Airport",
        "New Tokyo International Airport",
        "Shin Tokyo Kokusai Kuko",
        "NRT",
        "RJAA T"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Estes Kefauver introduced the bill that called for this amendment, which dealt with a body introduced in Article II, Section 1 of the Constitution. Other than Minnesota, the central region in question in this amendment was the only source of electoral votes for Walter Mondale in 1980. A Home Rule Act established the office of mayor in the area affected by this amendment. For ten points, name this 1961 F amendment that provided voting rights to the District of Columbia.",
      "answer": "23rd Amendment"
    },
    {
      "question": "These edible items were used to spread messages in a scheme conceived by Liu Bowen and future Hongwu Emperor Zhu Yuanzhang to overthrow the Yuan Dynasty. These edible items may have imprints of Lady Chang’e and are commonly eaten on the 15th day of a certain month. These food items received worldwide attention in 2019 when pro-democracy protestors in Hong Kong began using them as a symbol. A For ten points, name these Chinese cakes named after a celestial object.",
      "answer": [
        "Mooncake",
        "Yu`ebing"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "People of this ethnic group lost the Battle of Avarayr to the Sassanian empire. The greatest ruler of these people formed an alliance by marrying a non-Egyptian Cleopatra, prompting Lucius Licinius Lucullus to invade. The first Christian kingdom in the world was formed by this ethnic group, whose national symbol is Mount Ararat. The Orontid Dynasty was ruled by members of, for ten points, what Eurasian ethnic group based in and around Yerevan? R",
      "answer": "Armenians"
    },
    {
      "question": "Marshal W.F. Degan was murdered during this event, at which the sniper Lon Horiuchi controversially killed the central target’s pregnant wife Vicki. Culminating in the arrest of Kevin Harris and former Green Beret, Randy Weaver, this event and a similar event the following year involving David Koresh’s Branch Davidian Compound in Waco were sources of inspiration for the perpetrators of the Oklahoma City bombing. For ten points, name this eleven-day siege in 1992 in Idaho.",
      "answer": [
        "Ruby Ridge Siege",
        "answers including “Standoff,” “Incident,” etc. D"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "This man argued that supermajorities should be able to overturn Supreme Court decisions in his book Slouching Toward Gomorrah. According to Ted Kennedy, “Schoolchildren could not be taught about evolution” if this man was appointed to a post that opened with the retirement of Lewis Powell. After the failure of this man’s nomination to that post, Anthony Kennedy was chosen instead. For ten points, name this conservative whose Reagan-era Supreme Court nomination was not approved.",
      "answer": "Robert Bork T"
    }
  ],
  "q2": [
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "The most extreme members of this group sat on the highest seats of the National Assembly and were named “The Mountain.” C.L.R. James wrote aFbook titled for “Black” members of this group, one of whose leaders was killed by the “Angel of Assassination,” Charlotte Corday. This faction set up the Committee of Public Safety but fell in the Thermidorian Reaction. For ten points, name this faction in the French Revolution led by Maximilien Robespierre.",
        "answer": [
          "Jacobins",
          "Black Jacobins"
        ]
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "The Mountain, or Montagnards, stood in opposition to this group of relative moderates whose violent purge is considered the beginning of the Reign of Terror. A",
        "answer": "Girondins"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "Defiance of an early version of this law led to a mass migration to Cass County, Michigan. Prigg v Pennsylvania greatly weakened that early version of this law. The Wisconsin Supreme Court’s refusal to enforce this law was ruled unconstitutional in Ableman v Booth. This act was called the “Bloodhound Law” by abolitionists. For ten points name this act, part of the Compromise of 1850, that required Northerners to return runaway slaves to the South.",
        "answer": "Fugitive Slave Act of 1850 R"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "The Fugitive Slave Law Convention was held to oppose the Fugitive Slave Act and was chaired by this noted abolitionist, the author of My Bondage and My Freedom",
        "answer": "Frederick Douglass"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "Relief efforts after this event were assisted by the HMS Cardiff while on narcotics patrols in the West Indies. This event uprooted nearly every tree in the Kendall region. Lawton Chiles declared a state of emergency in response to this event that, while moving toward the Bahamas, became classified as D Category 5. The handling of this storm improved George H.W. Bush’s approval ratings in Dade County. For ten points, name this 1992 hurricane that heavily affected South Florida.",
        "answer": "Hurricane Andrew"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "After Lawton Chiles died in 1998, this Republican won election as governor of Florida and went on to become Florida’s first two-term Republican governor.",
        "answer": "John Ellis “Jeb” Bush T"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "In this modern-day country, Maha Bandula led foot-soldiers during the Battle of Danubyu. Following the collapse of the Pagan Empire, the Myinsaing Kingdom ruled this country for seventeen years. This country’s Arakan and Hanthawaddy kingdoms were conquered by its Toungoo Dynasty, whose official religion was Theravada Buddhism. King Mindon founded the city of Mandalay in, for ten points, what F country, whose kingdoms fought over the Irrawaddy Valley?",
        "answer": [
          "Republic of the Union of Myanmar",
          "Union of Burma,",
          "Pyidaunzu Thanmada Myama Nainngandaw"
        ]
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "This Nobel Peace Prize winner from Myanmar became a political prisoner after the military refused to hand over power when her NLD party won 81% of the seats in Parliament in 1990.",
        "answer": [
          "Daw Aung San Suu Kyi be lenient on pronunciation,",
          "Amay Suu A"
        ]
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "A massive bronze door to a chapel at this location was designed by Lib´eral Brunant, the primary architect of this location. Cannons designed by Jean Baptiste de Gribeauval and Sylvain Val´ee can be seen in this location’s Mus´ee de l’Arm´ee. A 107-foot tall church designed by Jules Hardouin-Mansart at this location is the largest in Paris. For ten points, name this former military hospital in Paris’s seventh arrondissement which is the site of Napoleon’s tomb.",
        "answer": [
          "Les Invalides",
          "Hˆotel national des Invalides R"
        ]
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Also buried in Les Invalides is this Marshal of France, the Allied Supreme Commander in World War One",
        "answer": "Ferdinand Foch"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This man noted, “We cannot all be Descartes or Kant, but we all want happiness” in his essay, “The Path of the Law.” This man’s opinion in Buck v. Bell, supporting compulsory sterilization, came after a 1919 First Amendment case in which this man wrote about the “substantive evils” caused by “shouting D fire in a crowded theater.” For ten points, name this Supreme Court justice who outlined the doctrine of “clear and present danger” in the case Schenck v. U.S.",
        "answer": "Oliver Wendell Holmes, Jr."
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Holmes’s opinion in Buck v. Bell confirmed that compulsory sterilization of those deemed “unfit” did not violate this clause of the Fourteenth Amendment which prohibits arbitrary deprivation.",
        "answer": "Due Process T"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "A lost epic titled for this mythical event is believed to be a creation of the semi-legendary bard, Eumelus of Corinth. The Orphic hymns describe this event as being preceded by the murder of Zagreus by this event’s title beings. During this event, Gaia advised Zeus to free the Cyclopes and the Hundred Handed ones. Along with the Gigantomachy, this conflict was depicted on the Parthenon Friezes. For ten F points, name this war from Greek mythology, which ended with Zeus overthrowing Cronus.",
        "answer": "Titanomachy"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Zeus cast the Titans into this place, a deep abyss “as far beneath earth as earth is beneath heaven,” named for one of Hesiod’s primordial deities.",
        "answer": "Tartarus A"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This thinker wrote that he felt “a gentle, melancholy emotion” while meditating in Michigan in his essay, “Two Weeks in the Wilderness.” This man criticized the power of the legislative branch in a work he researched with Gustave de Beaumont while examining the prison system. In that work, this thinker wrote that fear arises from “soft despotism” and warned against a “tyranny of the majority.” For ten points, name this French author of Democracy in America.",
        "answer": "Alexis de Tocqueville"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Tocqueville succumbed to this infectious disease that also killed John Keats and Eleanor RooRsevelt, historically referred to as “consumption.”",
        "answer": [
          "Tuberculosis",
          "TB"
        ]
      }
    }
  ],
  "q3": [
    {
      "category": "Harlem",
      "prompt": "Name the...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "City that contains the neighborhood of Harlem F",
          "answer": "New York City"
        },
        {
          "question": "Period of artistic explosion that featured figures like Langston Hughes",
          "answer": "Harlem Renaissance"
        },
        {
          "question": "Mass movement of African-Americans from the South to neighborhoods like Harlem",
          "answer": [
            "The Great Northward Migration",
            "Black Migration A"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "Civil rights organization that awards the Spingarn Medal and operated one of its largest chapters in Harlem",
          "answer": [
            "NAACP",
            "National Association for the Advancement of Colored People"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "Common nickname for East Harlem due to its predominantly Latin American population",
          "answer": "Spanish Harlem"
        },
        {
          "question": "Civil rights leader who founded the Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters while living in Harlem R",
          "answer": "Asa Philip Randolph"
        },
        {
          "question": "Surname of pastor, Adam Clayton, who served Harlem in Congress and names Harlem’s tallest building",
          "answer": "Powell"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "category": "Post-Franco Spain",
      "prompt": "After the death of Francisco Franco...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "This autonomous region tried to leave Spain numerous times, including in a 2017 referendum F",
          "answer": "Catalonia"
        },
        {
          "question": "This political faction of his lost power after defeating the Liberals in the Spanish Civil War",
          "answer": "Nationalists"
        },
        {
          "question": "This far-right party with a name meaning “voice” gained some seats in 2019",
          "answer": "Vox A"
        },
        {
          "question": "This monarch came to power and oversaw the Spanish transition to democracy",
          "answer": "Juan Carlos I"
        },
        {
          "question": "This Socialist served as Prime Minister from 1982-96",
          "answer": "Felipe Gonz´alez"
        },
        {
          "question": "SEAT [SAY-aht] helped Spain’s economic miracle by making these products in cooperation with Volkswagen R",
          "answer": [
            "Cars",
            "automobiles"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "This 1981 coup against the democratic election of a Prime Minister was defeated",
          "answer": [
            "23-F coup",
            "Tejerazo"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "Morocco held this demonstration, giving them control of most of Spanish Sahara",
          "answer": "Green March D T"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "category": "Zionism",
      "prompt": "Name the...",
      "questions": [
        {
          "question": "Country established as a Jewish homeland F",
          "answer": "State of Israel"
        },
        {
          "question": "Year in which that country was founded and fought the Arab League in a war",
          "answer": "1948"
        },
        {
          "question": "Father of Zionism and first president of the World Zionist Organization",
          "answer": "Theodor Herzl A"
        },
        {
          "question": "British Prime Minister who names a declaration pledging support for a Jewish homeland",
          "answer": [
            "Arthur Balfour",
            "1st Earl of Balfour"
          ]
        },
        {
          "question": "British banking family whose member Lionel was the recipient of that declaration",
          "answer": "Rothschild"
        },
        {
          "question": "Tenet of zionism that refers to Jews immigrating to Israel, defined literally as “going up”",
          "answer": "Making aliyah R"
        },
        {
          "question": "British Zionist leader and first president of Israel who met with President Truman to obtain US support",
          "answer": "Chaim Azriel Weizmann"
        },
        {
          "question": "Odessa-born Zionist leader who founded Revisionist Zionism and co-founded the Jewish legion",
          "answer": "Ze’ev Jabotinsky D T"
        }
      ]
    }
  ],
  "q4": [
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) During this event, posters that read “I AM A MAN” were created. This event was sparked by the death of Echol Cole and RobeFrt Walker. Jerry Wurf was a local NAACP leader arrested during this event. That prompted one man to give a speech during this event in which he said he “may not get (20 pts)",
        "there with you” but that he had “seen the promised land.” In the aftermath of this event, which led to the (10 pts)",
        "“I’ve Been to the Mountaintop” speech, James Earl Ray committed a felony. For ten points, name this 1968 strike that shortly preceded the assassination of Martin Luther King."
      ],
      "answer": [
        "1968 Memphis Sanitation Strike",
        "answers indicating a strike of sanitation workers in Memphis A"
      ]
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) A 1981 bill to make this man an honorary citizen of the United States was sponsored by Congressman Tom Lantos. This man studied architecture at the University of Michigan before he became an employee of a branch office of the Holland Bank in Haifa. This man was reported to have died in (20 pts)",
        "Lubyanka two years after being arrested by the Soviets. This diplomat is believed to have been arrested due to his work for the (10 pts)",
        "CIA while in Budapest. For ten points, name this Swedish special envoy to Hungary who saved thousands of Jews during the Nazi occupation. ANRSWER: Raoul Wallenberg (3) Wally Herbert challenged this man’s claims in Noose of Laurels, and such claims of falsification are supported by pieces of loose paper inserted in a journal. With twenty-three other men, including Ross Gilmore Martin, this man set out from Bartlett Camp to (+) race north. Frederick Cook claimed to have reached this man’s goal a year earlier. This explorer was accompanied by his “first man,” who wrote (*) A Negro Explorer at the North Pole. This companion of Matthew Henson has been the subject of controversy over whether he reached the North Pole first. For ten points, name this American explorer. D"
      ],
      "answer": "Robert Peary"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This empire was deceived at the Battle of Parwan when straw warriors were used by Shigi Qutugu. In this empire’s city of Otrar, Governor Inalchuq’s arrest of all Mongol caravans led to an invasion. The last ruler of this empire was Jalal al-Din Mingburnu, whose city of Urgench faced a massacre in which (20 pts)",
        "50,000 enemies were given the task of killing 24 people each. Anushtegin Gharchai founded this Central Asian empire, centered south of the Aral Sea near the (10 pts)",
        "Karakum desert. For ten points, name this medieval Persian empire of Mamluk origin that collapsed when it was crushed by Genghis Khan."
      ],
      "answer": [
        "Khwarazmian Empire",
        "Dynasty",
        "Khwarezmid Empire",
        "Dynasty,",
        "Anushtegin Dynasty before mentioned,",
        "Khrarazmian shahs",
        "kings T"
      ]
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) Heinz Valk coined the name for these events, and one of the outcomes of these events was recognized by Iceland before any other nation. During these events, the 50th anniversary of the signing of the Molotov-Ribbentrop Pact led to a 2 million person (20 pts)",
        "human chain. The epic hero Lacplesis inspired a rock opera popularized during this event that also included F Alo Mattisen’s “Five Patriotic Songs” at the (10 pts)",
        "Tartu Pop Festival. Lasting from roughly 1987 to 1991, for ten points, give the common name for a series of events that contributed to the independence of the Baltic states."
      ],
      "answer": "Singing Revolutions"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This man won 38 of the 44 cases in which he represented the U.S. government as Solicitor General. This man filled the vacancy when Harlan Fiske Stone was appointed to A replace Charles Evans Hughes as (20 pts)",
        "Chief Justice. That occurred four years before this man was made chief prosecutor of a set of proceedings whose targets were executed or sent to (10 pts)",
        "Spandau Prison. Pressing charges against men like Hermann Goring, for ten points, name this attorney and Supreme Court Justice who represented the U.S. at the Nuremberg Trials."
      ],
      "answer": "Robert Houghwout Jackson"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) Palladiy Kafarov was the first to translate one work with this title from Chinese and bring it to the west. The writer of another work with this title told of the Italian campaigns of RBelisarius in his The History of the Wars. One of these works with this title is the oldest surviving work in a language based in the (20 pts)",
        "Khalka dialect. The other work with this title describes a scene in a theatre where trained geese ate food off of Empress (10 pts)",
        "Theodora. For ten points, give the title of these works, one of which is a Mongol chronicle and the other of which was written by the Byzantine scholar, Procopius."
      ],
      "answer": [
        "Secret History",
        "The Secret History of the Mongols"
      ]
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) During this event, scholar Eduard Goldstu¨cker tested one leader’s commitment to the Dfreedom of the press when he criticized President Anton´ın Novotny´ on national television. During this event, journalist Ludv´ık Vacul´ık [VATS-oo-leek] released a manifesto called (20 pts)",
        "“Two Thousand Words.” In the aftermath of this event, Gustav Husak [HOO-shock] instituted the “normalization” period. During this period, (10 pts)",
        "Alexander Dubcek [DOOB-check] tried to institute “Socialism with a human face.” For ten points, name this period of political liberalization and protests in the capital of Czechoslovakia."
      ],
      "answer": "Prague Spring T"
    }
  ]
}